Solomon Sunday Chinoyerem

FRONTEND ENGINEER

SUMMARY

An experienced and Progress-driven Software engineer with the view of providing solutions to practical problems and achieving organizational goals. With over 4 years of experience in web & mobile application development and providing support to top companies and banking sectors in Africa.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality

Nigerian

Location

Ikeja, Lagos State

CONTACT

- schinoyerem007@gmail.com
- +2348065907281
- https://www.thedrycleanersson.com/resume
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/solomonsunday
- https://github.com/solomonsunday

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer (Lead) (https://int.app.persistafrica.com/)

EXQUIS APP FACTORY LTD

2021 - Present

- Transformed designs from Figma into responsive, user-friendly, and interactive web pages
- Assisting other developers to resolve bugs they are having in their code.
- Implemented reusable code using Nextjs, Redux, Styled Component, CSS, Bootstrap
- Working with the backend developers and the UI/UX designers to improve the experience of the application
- Improve the performance of the legacy application

Front End Engineer (Lead) (https://www.woozeee.com/)

WOOZEEE LTD 2020 - 2021

- Transformed designs from Figma into responsive, user-friendly, and interactive web pages
- Assist other developers to resolve bugs they are having in their code.
- Implemented reusable code using Reactjs, Tailwind, Firebase, Cloudinary, Redux
- Converted a Reactjs monolithic application to a micro frontend application for the team to adopt.
- Review and merged PR to the codebase using Git version control

• FULL STACK ENGINEER (https://www.kapsuulconnect.com/)

NETOP BUSINESS SYSTEM LTD 2018 -2020

Worked with a team of developers that developed KAPSUUL an application that helps pharmacists, and pharmaceutical organizations bring their teams together in a frictionless environment to get more done. the application was built using React and Redux, Nodejs, bootstrap 5.

- Used feedback from end users to improve the user experience of the company's legacy application that is in use by top banks in Nigeria,
- Participated in the documentation and designed the warehouse system of a multimillion-naira supply chain application currently in use by MDSone of the bigggest Logistics companies in Nigeria.
- Using my excellent communication and interpersonal skills I provided support for organizations using the company's application

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY, AWKA 2013 - 2017

FrontEnd Developer

UDACITY 2018 – 2018

Complete Next.js Developer

ZERO TO MASTERY ACADEMY 2021 -2022

Nanodegree, Cloud DevOps Engineer

UDACITY 2022 - 2022

TECH SKILLS

Javascript, Reactjs, React-native, AngularJs, Nextjs, Redux Toolkit, React-Redux, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Figma, Bootstrap, NodeJs, NestJs C#, Postgres, MSSQl, Version Control, AWS, GCP, Docker, Agile/scrum.